准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
土豆泡芙
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜指导
统筹
联合监制
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
看不见了
I can't see
妈妈
Mama
爸爸
Papa
不要
No
炸药厂
裤头村期待已久的炸药厂
Bikini Bottom's long-awaited dynamite factory
现在开业
is now open
小心
Look out
泡芙老师  从上面可以看到你家
Hey, Mrs. Puff, I can see your house from up here
真是厉害
Look at that
帮我省下了往返通勤的时间
You saved me a commute
你还是先走吧
Just let yourself out
要是你确定的话
Well, if you're sure
明天再见  泡芙老师
See you tomorrow, Mrs. Puff
他可能真的完全教不会
Maybe he really is unteachable
我放弃
I give up
不行  泡芙
No, Puff
还早着呢
not yet
你可是个驾校教练
You're a driving instructor
教导那小子可是你的重责大任
Instructing that boy is your duty
你只需要一点引导就行了
You just need a little guidance
宇宙向你问好
The universe greets you
让我来引导你的天体运动
Allow me to guide your celestial vessel
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
害得
driving
我
me
疯掉了
crazy
泡芙老师啊
Oh, Mrs. Puff
想脱离你这种状况
Perhaps it would help
就需要想办法陪着海绵宝宝
if you find a way to be with SpongeBob
但同时又不在海绵宝宝身边  行吗
without being with SpongeBob, hmm?
好
Okay
欢迎你以后再来用钱来烦我
Feel free to annoy me for money again soon
再见
Goodbye
压力少点了
Less stress
陪着海绵宝宝
Being with SpongeBob
同时又不在海绵宝宝身边
without being with SpongeBob
得怎么做
But how?
音乐从哪传来的
Where is that music coming from?
潜水艇
A submarine?
这样就有办法了
That gives me an idea
我就知道
I knew it
有水手的地方都会有土豆
Where there are sailors, there are always potatoes
小尖尖玻璃刀
搞什么鬼
Qu'est-ce que c'est?
好了
There
这样应该能成
That should do it
泡芙老师
Oh, Mrs. Puff
好久不见
It's been so long
是不是很想我
Did you miss me?
我可太想了  海绵宝宝
Oh, yes, SpongeBob
真是想死你了
I missed you so much
很高兴能再见到你
It's so good to see you
从这见
from here
你买了新帽子吗
Did you get a new hat?
显得你眼睛更漂亮了
It really brings out all your eyes
好了
All right
该专心看路了  我的优秀小笨蛋
Time to focus on the road, my excellent little noodle
我一定不会辜负你期望的
I must live up to your noodle-spectations
起点
怎么样
How was that?
表现太好了
That was very good
好  在这边右转
Okay, take a right here
现在继续右转
Now keep going right
感觉太对了
Feels right to me
太好了
Yes, it does
我现在能补剧了
Now I can catch up on my stories
德韦恩
Dwayne
我唯一的心之所爱
The only thing I've ever loved
就是把你脑袋砸得四分五裂
Is a skull-cracking smackdown
这样就对了
That's right
右
一直右转
Keep going right?
好啊
All right
对
Yeah
没错  海绵宝宝
Sure, SpongeBob
天啊  感觉我真的快掌握
Boy, I really feel like I'm getting the hang
右转的技巧了
of this turning-right thing
都破我开船不出船祸最长时间记录了
This is the longest I've ever driven without crashing
一个都不剩了
There's none left
剩了
Left
左
左转
Left?
可我还在练右转啊
But I'm still working on right
你真觉得我做好准备了吗
Do you really think I'm ready?
慢
小心驾驶
对
Yeah
好  那我就左转了
Okay, if you think so
对不起
Sorry about that
有些人真是费尽心思
Some people will do anything
想开进多乘员专用道
to use the carpool lane
享用
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
你的车技完美无瑕
Your driving is immaculate
一直右转就行了
Just keep turning right
这个我很会
I'm great at that
上品瓷器
裤头村监狱
右转要开得稳稳的
Keep that righty nice and tight-y
稳稳右转
Tightening my rightening
今天一定是我当教练以来
This is the most fulfilling day
最满意的一天了
I've ever had as a teacher
你吞到虫子了吗
Swallowed a bug, huh?
各单位注意
Attention all units--
正在发生严重交通违法行为
major traffic violations in progress
请尽快追捕
Please pursue as fast as possible
停
学员驾驶员
这一定就是进阶课程了
This must be an advanced lesson
多节指关节
每夜都打架
酒馆
就是他
That's him--
旁边坐了个土豆的浑蛋
the jerk with the spud
大家抓住他
Let's get him, boys
这座极具历史意义的炸药厂
This historic dynamite factory
开业一整天以来都没出事故
has been open for one entire day with no accidents
是不是很神啊
Isn't that amazing?
插入通话  船员
Breaker, breaker, Cabin Boy
左满舵
Hard to port
收到  泡芙老师
A 10-4, Mrs. Puff
我都老得不想玩这个了
I'm gettin' too old for this
我们中断摔跤夹头撕心裂肺电视剧
We interrupt "Headlocks and Heartbreaks"
裤头村快讯
插播一则紧急新闻快讯
with an emergency news bulletin
超速海绵与土豆罪犯致全裤头村恐慌
High-speed sponge terrorizes Bikini Bottom
with potato prisoner--
群众最后目击到他在克拉肯大道上
last seen pursued by band of bandit bikers
被鬼火骑手追赶
along Kraken Avenue
谁知道他接下来会袭击何处
Who knows where he may strike next?
突发新闻 疯子横冲直撞
什
Wha
我的腿
My leg
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
喂
Hello?
海神王啊
Oh, Neptune
不戴这顶休闲假发了
Enough of this leisure wig
改戴追杀假发
Time for the pursuit wig
情境式假发
火爆
火炮操纵杆
我是驾校教练
I'm a driving instructor
我要征用这辆车
and I'm commandeering this vehicle
明白  鸡冠头大妈
I can dig it, mohawk mama
快掉头
Turn around
就听你的
Whatever you say
天啊
Oh, dear
肉汁
泡芙老师
Mrs. Puff
你被削成泥了
You've been mashed
她还活着
She's alive
你复原能力太强了  泡芙老师
You sure are resilient, Mrs. Puff
从现在起  海绵宝宝
From now on, SpongeBob
我要负起驾校教练的重责大任
I'll uphold my duty as your driving instructor
确保你行船安全
to keep you safe on the road
等一下
Wait a minute
你是火爆泡芙
You're Puff the Tuff
能在我石膏上面签名吗
Will you sign my cast?
我爱你
I love you
好一个神人
What a legend
你们好
Hi, boys
看样子你们把事情都控制住了
Looks like you got things under control here
快逃
Let's scram
流程我都知道
I know the drill
那
So
你干了什么才进来的
what are you in for?
万能神油
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
动画总监
指导总监
统筹
联合监制
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
蟹堡王
干得好啊  小子
Nice work, boy-o
蟹堡王干净得不得了啊
She looks cleaner than a freshly scraped hull
蟹老板好  我
Hello, Mr. Krabs, I--
你的脚
Your feet
好险啊
That was close
你差点把黏液
You almost tracked goo
踩得干干净净的蟹堡王到处都是
all over your nice, clean restaurant
补救得不错吧
Good save, huh?
看来这滩黏液就是罪魁祸首
Looks like this puddle here is the culprit
你放心  蟹老板
Don't worry, Mr. K
我一下子就能清理干净
I'll have her cleaned up in no time
洗洁精
好
Okay
把这个倒进去  然后就
you just pour this in here, and--
还说什么今天真是美好
"It's a beautiful day," you said
还说什么得去外面搞什么邪恶科学
"Why not do some evil science outside?" you said
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
你在搞什么鬼
What in Neptune's navel are you doing?
抱歉  痞老板
Sorry, Plankton
我在帮蟹老板清理这滩黏液
I was just cleaning up this goo puddle for Mr. Krabs
看着不像黏液
That doesn't look like goo
倒像是石油
It looks like oil
我的天啊  凯伦
Holy moly, Karen
我们脚下就是金山银山
We're sittin' on a mountain of moolah
石油是我的  听见没
That oil's mine, you hear?
是我员工先发现的
My employee found it
而且还是在我地产上的
and besides, it's on me property
你先别急  老螃蟹
Not so fast, Krabs
石油是我的
That's my oil
而且还在我地产上
and it's on my property
咕噜
其实你们都说错了
Actually, you're both wrong
这根本不是石油
It's not oil at all
居然不是
It's not?
根据我的分析
According to my analysis
这是蟹黄堡油与海霸糊流的混合物
it's a combination of
Krabby Patty grease and Chum runoff
是你们两家餐厅
which your two restaurants
几十年来渗进地底下的结果
have been leaking into the ground for decades
所以说这就是不值钱的地沟老油了
So it's just worthless old grease?
并不会不值钱
I wouldn't call it "worthless"
它有着极高的黏度
It has a high viscosity index
还有惊为天人的提味特性
and impressive flavor-imparting characteristics
所以说很值钱了
So its "worthful"?
对
Yes
然而这滩地沟油似乎
however, the deposit appears to be
得两家平均分配才行
evenly split between your restaurants
好吧痞老板
Well, Plankton
看样子要想赚大钱
looks like if we want to make a lot of money
就必须得成为
We'll have to do it as
合作伙伴
Partners
漫长的几天后
快啊  老螃蟹
Come on, Krabs
这东西一定有咱俩公认的用途
There's got to be some use for this stuff we can agree on
就卖给军方吧
Let's sell it to the military
想象一下
Imagine--
火焰喷射器燃料
fuel for flamethrowers
杀手机器人润滑油
lubricant for killer robots
发出薯条香气的炸弹
bombs that smell like French fries
就用这油来增进蟹堡王的生意
We'll use it to boost business at The Krusty Krab
可口的全新三明治配料
a flavorful new sandwich topping
美味
好吃的全新奶昔
a savory new milkshake
还有厕所的全新芳香
and a lovely new scent for the restrooms
不行
Oh, no
不能用我的油
We're not using my grease
给你家蟹堡王拉客
to drive customers to your restaurant
你
You
我应该
Why, I ought to
天啊  看不出来
Oh, gosh, I don't see
你们为什么非得只找一种用途
why you need to find just one use for this stuff
我所有用途全都要
I started using it for everything
什么
What?
牙膏
Toothpaste
沐浴露
bodywash
除臭剂
deodorant
鞋油
shoe polish
能敷一整晚的面膜
all-night face mask
小蜗
小蜗的早餐
Gary's breakfast
我自己的早餐
my own breakfast
我自己
还治好了我滑囊炎
It even cured my bursitis
我想说的是
What I mean is
既然你们所有用途全都要
if you can use it for anything
不然就把它当万能神油卖吧
why not sell it for everything?
蟹痞博士奇迹万能神油
不错
Not bad
最好引点客人来  尤金
Well, we better get some customers here, Eugene
我熬夜一整晚画了那个牌子
I was up all night painting that sign
有点信心嘛  痞老板
Have a little faith, Plankton
快看  午餐高峰期
Behold, the lunch rush
该来干活了
Time to get to work
不好意思  大姐
Pardon me, ma'am
要不要买点蟹痞博士奇迹万能神油
but how about some
Dr. Krabton's Miracle Everything Juice
让你的小天使们静一静
to quiet the little angels?
蟹痞博士可以帮你把船修好
Why, Dr. Krabton can fix up your boat for you
看吧
See?
好了
There you go
完好如初
Good as new
还真的有用
Say, it really works
为万能神油欢呼三声
Three cheers for Everything Juice
万岁
Hooray
我们要买一份
We'll take one
看咱赚了这么多钱  老螃蟹
Look at all this cash, Krabs
我们发财了
We're rich
还不够发
Not rich enough
我们要开始巡回演出了
We got to take our show on the road
好了  痞老板
All right, Plankton
让我这个真正的推销员给你好好示范
Let a real salesman show you how it's done
尤金
Eugene?
这可太惊喜了
What a surprise
今天没约我出去吃午餐  对吧
We don't have a lunch date today, do we?
不是跟我约
Not with me
是要跟划算约
Your date today is with value
假如我告诉你有一样产品
Suppose I told you there was one product
可以给你所有船都加上油
that could fuel all your boats
方便重新粉刷旧灯塔
Reinvigorate old lighthouse paint jobs
还能覆盖住
And even cover up those
眼睛周围的皱纹
Maturation lines around your eyes
我抹
Plank
怎么敢这样
How dare you?
给我来十瓶
Give me ten bottles
你表现可太好了  老螃蟹
You did pretty good back there, Krabs
不过现在得瞧瞧大师的本领
But now it's time to watch a master
好啊
Gladly
等他来了再提醒我
Let me know when he gets here
你好
Howdy
你好啊  珊迪
Greetings, Sandra
我来这是要向你介绍我们最新发明
I am here to tell you about our latest invention
可以帮你的草地施肥
It'll fertilize your lawn
擦亮你的树屋玻璃
Polish your dome glass
还能让你最老的坚果
And give even your oldest nuts
焕发出新鲜采摘的光泽
that fresh-picked shine
这就是蟹痞博士奇迹万能神油
It's Dr. Krabton's Miracle Everything Juice
我可不是土包子  痞老板
I ain't some hayseed, Plankton
我是科学家
I'm a scientist
我不相信奇迹
I don't believe in miracles
它还能让制氧机
Well, but it can also keep oxygen machines
工作在最佳状态
running in top shape
我倒挺喜欢呼吸的
Well, I do like breathin'
我买一整箱
I'll take a whole case
上门推销耗的时间太久了
This door-to-door stuff's taking too long
必须玩得更大点
We got to go big
怎么个大法
How big?
盛大音乐剧
Musical big
蟹痞博士奇迹万能神油
你好先生  想不想了解
Hey, there, mister, would you like to know
一样特别神奇的东西
About a very a special something
让你烦恼都消散
That makes all your problems go away?
什么东西
What is it?
就是万能神油
It's Everything Juice
什么
What?
你好大姐  我能不能帮忙
Hey, there, madam, can I help you out
帮你洗洗假牙
With those false teeth of yours
想必你一定难以欢呼
It must be very hard to shout hooray
庆祝万能神油
For Everything Juice
能不能让我声音听着更可怕点吗
Can it make my voice sound much more creepy?
大概行
Probably
能不能让我家琪琪不发臭味
Will it fix the smell of my pet Kiki?
买一买瞧一瞧
Buy it and see
确实
Indeed
孩子们好  你们好像很需要
Hey, there, son, looks like you might need
找到滑腻腻的办法
To find some slickening solution
让你们弹珠滚得飞快
So your marbles can get up to speed today
试试万能神油
Try Everything Juice
不好意思  我发现你比较想
Pardon me, but I see you chose
留着长长的鼻毛
Not to trim that rather lengthy hair
长到探出鼻孔  但没关系
Protruding from your nose, but that's okay
有万能神油
With Everything Juice
这要多少钱
How much does it cost?
要不少
Quite a lot
我不管
I don't care
存货全都卖给我
Give me everything you've got
是的  我的朋友
Yes, my friends
这东西一级棒
this is the greatest stuff
是个天大的奇迹
It's a wonder, it's a miracle
想要多少都不够
You just can't have enough
那就快来
So we say hey
马上来买
Get some today
不需要借口
There's no excuse
大家都需要万能神油
Everyone needs Everything Juice
蟹痞博士
一百万零一
A million one
一百万零二
a million two
一百万零三
a million three
尤金  这就是友情的感觉吗
Eugene, is this what friendship feels like?
应该就是了  谢尔顿
Perhaps it is, Sheldon
应该就是了
Perhaps it is
扔钱大战
Money fight
你们来这干什么
What are you all doing in here?
我们是不满意的顾客
We are unsatisfied customers
看看你家油对我空气干的好事
Just look at what your grease did to my air
你家油害我眼睛都红肿了
Your grease gave me pink eye
起码你
Well, at least your
皱纹没了
Maturation lines are gone
我要再买两瓶
I'll take two more bottles
不行
No more
你们两个已经把全裤头村都毁了
You two have ruined the whole town
我们要退钱
We want our money back
我就知道你会搞砸
I knew you would mess this up
你老是把事情都搞砸
You always mess things up
我
Me?
我才没想出那首破歌
I'm not the one who came up with that lousy song
一定是油量不够了
Must be running low on grease
又不是我
Well, it wasn't me
把它当灭火器补充液卖的
who sold it as fire extinguisher recharging fluid
好了好了
All right, all right
可又不是我
But I'm not the one
把它卖给中学生治青春痘的
who sold it as acne treatment to high schoolers
但你确实把它当饮用维生素卖了
But you did market it as drinkable vitamins
就这样
That's it
这场友情结束了
This friendship is over
又要来当死对头了
We are mortal enemies once more
好啊
Fine by me
我再也不想见到你了
I don't want to see you ever again, ever
都是你的错
This is all your fault
你害咱困在这了
You trapped us in here
真希望我从来没见过你
I wish I'd never met you
我加倍希望没见过你
That goes double for me
天啊
Oh, boy
三位好朋友一起被活埋一辈子
The three best friends buried alive together forever
全都多亏了
and it's all thanks to
万能神油
Everything Juice